## Patrick A. Levell

1319 Edgewood Avenue • Florence, South Carolina 29501 home 843.665.2327 • cellular 843.615.4980 • fax 803.753.9167 • email <a href="mailto:patrick@levell.net">patrick@levell.net</a> • web <a href="mailto:www.levell.net">www.levell.net</a>

### **Profile**

Results-driven **Computer Systems Analyst** / **Developer** with broad-based experience in enhancing system functionality and end-user productivity. Accomplished professional who has earned a reputation for consistently meeting and exceeding aggressive objectives. Effective communicator possessing excellent interpersonal and relationship-building skills.

## **Education**

DeVry Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois

1995

**Bachelor of Science**, Computer Information Systems Cumulative GPA 3.62 (Honours)

## Computer Skills

| System Software            | Applications        | Development Tools         |
|----------------------------|---------------------|---------------------------|
| ➤ J.D. Edwards OneWorld Xe | ➤ Visio             | Visual Studio IDE         |
| ERP                        | ➤ Excel             | Visual Basic, VB.Net, C++ |
| ➤ Windows 95/2000/XP/2003  | > Access            | ➤ SQL Server 7/2000       |
| ➤ IIS/SharePoint           | Microsoft Office    | Crystal Reports           |
| ➤ PC/MS-DOS                | Quattro Pro         | Rational Rose             |
| ➤ QNX/UNIX                 | Paradox for Windows | ObjectPAL                 |
| > VAX VMS/DCL              | Quicken             | Borland C++ OWL, Turbo C  |
| Amiga Workbench            | ➤ dBASE III+/IV     | > FORTRAN                 |
|                            |                     |                           |

## **Professional Experience**

NUCOR Vulcraft - Florence, Florence, South Carolina

1997 to 2007

### Computer Systems Analyst / Developer

- ➤ Designing, developing, implementing, testing, and maintaining custom applications and reports for J.D. Edwards OneWorld ERP/MRP, Drafting, Engineering, EMS/QMS, and other business systems within this steel manufacturing organization.
- ➤ Using J.D.Edwards Event Rules, Form Designer, and Report Writer in combination with the development of "add-on" specialized report & application development using SQL queries, Excel, Access and VB/VB.Net/SQL Server.
- ➤ Working closely with users to define and "fine tune" requirements. Writing specifications, developing, testing and implementing applications.
- Creating end-user documentation.
- ➤ Providing training and supporting end-users on various JD Edwards modules including Financial, MRP, Sales, Purchasing, and Inventory.

Krolman Inc., Toronto, Ontario

1995 to 1997

## **Contract Windows Programmer**

➤ Designing, developing, testing, and maintaining custom CRM application using Borland C++, Paradox and ObjectPAL.

# **ERP Project Highlights**

Custom extensions or modifications on JD Edwards OneWorld Xe using OMW, Event Rules, Form Designer, and Report Writer include the following:

- ➤ Job Master Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards, summarizing customer account and project information in credit, sales, finance, engineering, and manufacturing systems, improving documentation and communication between departments; Created a user manual and 25-minute training video for this application using Snaglt, MS Publisher, and MS PowerPoint
- ➤ Production Scheduler fixed sales, purchasing, manufacturing, delivery date issues; linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Input; resulting in fewer problems between Sales and Drafting

- Completed, Not Shipped (CNS) the Finished Goods report every nut & bolt in the plant is processed by this custom JD Edwards report—a critical piece of Vulcraft's month-end closing procedures; the Controller was using five other reports to get this information until CNS was fixed; month-end closing time was reduced by at least 20%; this report became an integral part of testing system changes in JD Edwards
- ➤ Material Resource Planning (MRP) troubleshooting, modifying, and performance-enhancing on this suite of batch applications, to reconcile sales, purchasing, manufacturing, and shipping dates, and reduce execution time & system resource requirements, as this is a resource hog
- ➤ The "Havens" Report a custom management report in JD Edwards, providing in-depth credit analysis of large and/or problematic customer accounts, with two sections—one for the customer, and one for top-level management
- ➤ 180-Day Weighted Average a custom financial report in JD Edwards for calculating customer credit scores, based on their last six months of credit history
- > Over 40 Days a custom financial report in JD Edwards for identifying overdue accounts
- ➤ Deck Inventory a custom JD Edwards financial (MRP) report for the Controller and Purchasing Agent, detailing current and projected raw material requirements
- ➤ Fab Schedule the weekly production schedule from which most office activity stems; two specialized versions of this report created for Drafting and Shop Order; ties in to Manufacturing, Customer Service, Job Master, Drafting, and Shop Order Inquiry screens
- ➤ Drafting Inquiry added additional fields for tracking approval drawings, and signaling Production Scheduler whether drawings are in-process, out for approval, or back from approval; linked to the Job Master Inquiry and Shop Order Inquiry screens; resulting in providing Production Scheduler with up-to-the minute information for scheduling purposes
- Shop Order Inquiry added additional fields for tracking bills of materials (aka. Shop orders) through the engineering design program (outside of JD Edwards); linked to Job Master Inquiry and Drafting Inquiry screens; resulting in much improved traceability and fewer interruptions in Data Entry from Drafting and Shop Order, asking for information
- Shipping Inquiry a management tool in JD Edwards combining bill of lading, sales, and shipping data for much improved searchability
- ➤ Daily Shipments a key custom JDE financial report used for invoicing, reported tons & dollars sold, tons & dollars shipped, freight amount and tax-exemption status
- ➤ SO SF Compare a custom JDE application for comparing what was sold to what was built & shipped; used primarily on large jobs to show the dollar amount left to be invoiced
- > Re-price Program a custom JDE application for re-pricing jobs, typically used when design requirements change

# **Custom Application Highlights**

Custom development using MS Excel/Access/. Net include the following:

- ➤ Internal Audit Manager a custom MS Access database application for managing internal audits of quality and environmental management systems; generates checklists, audit questions, and audit reports
- ➤ Inventory Tracking System a custom MS Excel spreadsheet application to analyze supplier promised & actual delivery dates using data from inventory and cost of quality spreadsheets; results delivered using charts, graphs, and pivot tables
- ➤ NUVU BoM Transfer a stand-alone application using VB.Net & SQL queries to transfer XML data from NUVU bills of materials to the engineering design program, effectively getting NUVU (AutoCAD) to talk to the design program, written in FORTRAN, and still thinks it is running on punch cards; complete with installer and auto-update feature for local and satellite sales offices
- Shipping Route-out Prototype this was a tool to move the current delivery dispatches ("route-out") procedures from paper-based to electronic; prototyped in MS Access and later integrated into J.D. Edwards
- NUVU Installer a collection of shell scripts, HTML, and VB.Net programs to install NUVU on AutoCAD workstations, including network security and administrative shares. All the users had to do to install NUVU was click on a single web-link
- Joist Input Program a front-end to the engineering design program, written in VB5 utilizing a SQL Server database instead of the old flat-files; object model created using Rational Rose; prototyping done in MS Access

## **Special Projects**

- Recovered stolen Internet domain name for a Colorado-based real estate brokerage firm; the investigation tracked the domain records down in Australia, and the owner in Spain; assistance was obtained from the International Trade Administration at the US Department of Commerce
- Served as Senior Lead Internal Auditor for six years. Led the team to make the transition from ISO 9001:1994 to ISO 9001:2000, which included leading the team that re-wrote the quality manual, and moving the quality manual from paper-based to an interactive on-line system, using MS Internet Information Server (IIS), SharePoint, and FrontPage.
- ➤ Routinely served as corporate liaison with outside auditors of both our quality and environmental management systems.

#### **Volunteer Work**

Pee Dee Coalition Against Domestic Violence & Sexual Assault, Florence, South Carolina

2005

#### Volunteer Advocate

- ➤ Participating in Alternatives to Violence (ATV) program
- > Conducting in-take interviews for ATV program

Vulcraft News & Views 2000 to 2006

## Publisher, Editor, and Contributing Author

- > Writing a regular computer help column for Vulcraft employees
- > Reduced production costs by 97% in only 3 years

Brantford Amiga Users Group 1987 to 1988

## **Contributing Author**

> Researching and writing tutorials for submission

Queensway Baptist Youth Group, Brantford, Ontario 1986 to 1987

#### **Public Relations Coordinator**

- > Creating promotional materials for fund raising
- > Presenting reports at church business meetings

### **Affiliations**

Member, American Society for Quality
Student Member, Data Processing Management Association
1995

## **Active Pursuits**

- ➤ Maintaining computer systems for friends and associates
- > Hiking, all-terrain bicycling, travel of all sorts
- Developing a strong on-line presence on the internet